Guide to the Herbert Feis papers, 1952-1972
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
Herbert Feis papers
1952-1972
C0089
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
1.5 linear feet (1 box)
This collection contains research materials and correspondence of Herbert Feis, including three letters from Mrs. Feis to her husband's assistant, Arline Pratt.
Feis, Herbert, 1893-1972
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Arline Pratt.
Biographical Information
Born in 1893, Herbert Feis was a distinguished author and historian, whose work focused on American foreign policy and international economic affairs. Early in his career, Feis worked as Economic Advisor for International Affairs at the State Department under the Hoover and Roosevelt administrations. His thirteen published books include "The Road to Pearl Harbor" (1950), "Europe, the World's Banker, 1870-1914" (1964), "From Trust to Terror: The Onset of the Cold War" (1970), and the Pulitzer Prize-winning "Between War and Peace: The Potsdam Conference" (1960). Since his passing, the American Historical Association has named an award after Feis, the Herbert Feis Prize, which is awarded annually for excellence in public history and independent scholarship. He died in 1972.
Scope and Content
This collection contains research materials and correspondence of Herbert Feis, including three letters from Mrs. Feis to her husband's assistant, Arline Pratt.
Arrangement
Organized by subject and date.
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Feis, Herbert, 1893-1972.
Subjects:
Cold war.; International finance.; World War, 1939-1945.
Contents List
- Herbert Feis papers, 1952-1972
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, June 13, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Cards of 20 Russian paintings at the loan exhibition selected and given by Hanford, August 1975 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, February 11 (no year) (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 23, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, undated (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter on the Institute for Advanced Study letterhead from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, undated (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, August 7, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, May 6, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 29, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 7 (no year listed) (Box 1)
  - Letter from Nathan R. Einhorn to Arline Pratt, July 28, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, March 1, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, May 10, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Financial statements (consists of reimbursement for hotel expenses invoice stub), September 21, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, October 7, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 31, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, May 16, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, May 24, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, September 11, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 13, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Ruth Feis to Arline Pratt, undated (Box 1)
  - Letter from Ruth Feis to Arline Pratt, February 1, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, September 27, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, September 20, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Letter from W.J. Donohoe to Dr. Feis, July 31, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Mr. Donohoe, August 4, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, August 4, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis, undated (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline. Pratt, January 31, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Florence to Arline, March 7, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, Arpil 16, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Ruth Feis to Arline Pratt, March 7, 1972 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, June 24, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, June 20, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, January 14, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, January 31, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, March 1, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, June 16, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 16, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, July 2, 1962 (Box 1)
  - American Historical Review article by Herbert Feis, undated (Box 1)
  - Handwritten note from Herbert Feis, undated (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, June 25, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, March 11, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, April 25, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten letter from Herbert Feis to Arline Pratt, 1957 (Box 1)